

# **Ventsislav Georgiev**

Bulgaria +359 988 860 680 · ventsi.d.georgiev@gmail.com

← Linkedin, GitHub, Portfolio

Date / Place of birth 20/07/1990, Shumen Nationality Bulgarian

#### **Skills**

Highly Organized

Good Team Player

**Positive Support** 

**Good Communication** 

Creative Thinking

Good Attention To Detail

Ability to Work Under

Pressure

**Active Listening** 

Decision-making

Flexibility and Adaptability

#### Languages

Bulgarian

English

### **Profile**

I'm a Front-end Developer with over 3+ years of experience in web development. Knowledgeable in user-interface, determining the structure and design of web pages, building reusable code for future use, ensuring web design is optimized for smartphones and maintaining brand consistency throughout the design. Equipped with a diverse and promising skill-set. Proficient in an assortment of technologies, including JavaScript, HTML, CSS/SASS, React, WordPress, RESTful APIs, Redux, Shopify(basic) and Figma(basic), Atlassian, GitHub.

# **Employment History**

Web Content Administrator, Keitliest - Konstantin Andreev, Sofia

November 2013 - November 2014

Maintaining tourist and news web pages. Technologies used:

\* PHP \* MySQL \* WP \* JavaScript \* HTML \* CSS

#### Junior Front-end Developer, MEGEXme, Sofia/Shumen

February 2018 — January 2020

Development and maintenance of information web page and roadside assistance application. Created for the American market.

Technologies used: \* Node \* Express \* MongoDB \* Javascript \* HTML \* CSS/SCSS \* Reactjs \* Redux \*REST \* Atlassian

# Web Content Administrator Online Store , HashTagMother, Sofia/Shumen

March 2020 - October 2020

Creating and maintaining an online store. Designed to sell children's and baby clothes and toys. Technologies used: \* Shopify \* CSS \* Microsoft office \* HTML

## Education

High School Diploma , High School of Economics , Shumen September 2004 - May 2009

Bachelor, University of National and World Economy, Sofia

September 2009 — July 2013

#### **Hobbies**

I would say that I really enjoy being in the nature, particularly in the beautiful mountains, and visiting different historical places in Bulgaria. Also, I love football - both playing and watching it. I have a lot of friends who are keen on football so we tend to spend a lot of time together doing all kinds of things related to football. Of course, I never forget my family and relatives. As we are not living in the same town, I very often visit and help them with everything I can. Last but not least, I am currently very interested in cryptocurrencies.

## **Courses**

"The Complete JavaScript Course 2019: Build Real Projects ", Udemy January 2019 — March 2019

"Modern React with Redux [2019 Update], Udemy

July 2019 — September 2019

"Advanced React and Redux: 2019 Edition", Udemy

January 2020 — April 2020

"Advanced JavaScript Concepts", Udemy

August 2020 — October 2020

" Practical Web Design & Development: 7 Courses in 1- Basics ", Udemy

November 2020 — December 2020

**Driving Licence: B, Shumen** 

September 2008 — November 2008